# MUHAMMAD HAFIZ RUSLAN

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Throughout my 2-year-plus years career as software developer, I have focused on developing scalable and well documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively, but can also run with projects independently. Excited to provide knowledge with team and gain various experiences in order to create product.

#### **SKILLS**

Laravel Framework V5.2 - V9
Java (Android Studio)
MySQL, MongoDB
Javascript (ES6, React, Node.js)
HTML / CSS
Talend v8

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Phone : 019-233 4157

Email: hafizcoolman@gmail.com

LinkedIn : hafizruslan98 Address : Banting, Selangor

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### **PHP Developer**

Unijaya Resources Sdn Bhd (September 2021 - May 2023) Kuala Lumpur

- Worked as a senior full-stack developer and resident engineer
- Used Laravel framework v5.2 and v9 in most project.
- Served as knowledgeable advisor to 15+ staffs and interns, increased productivity and reputation of company
- Developed and maintained project that 6 heavy modules, integrated with complex flow, turned into easy-to-use project
- Provided specialized advice and analysis on technical decision that impacted 7 projects in term of increasing performance up to 170% faster and much stable
- Contributed 2 in-house package to create usable flow and server file handling which decreased time taken from turning prototype into development by 60%
- Created a sophisticated modular module from complex hardcoded existing module that make deployment duration of a new station from 2 months into 3 days
- Led a team of 3 people to create a helpdesk system inside an existing project in just 1 week which includes taking requirement with client and pushing to production
- Utilized Talend software to create detailed flow with parallel execution, in result of able pulling 100,000+ data from other website and stored in just 8 seconds.

#### **Internship Lead Programming**

Leadmind Sdn Bhd (March 2021 - August 2021) Cyberjaya, Selangor

- Worked as a solo developer.
- Used Java and Apache at first to manage company data.
- Upgraded to using MongoDB, Express, React JS and Node (MERN) for establish website in managing 1000+ leads.
- Assisted in improvising staff and client experiences by provide smooth surfing and fast algorithm functions.
- Learnt many skills in short period of time without guidance.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Universiti Teknologi Mara (UiTM) MELAKA KAMPUS JASIN

Bachelor Science in Computer Science March 2018 - August 2021 CGPA: 3.53

## Kolej Matrikulasi Selangor (KMS)

Sains PST Modul II Jun 2016 - Jun 2017 CGPA : 3.83